A Nutcracker Christmas is a drama, family, tv movie
film directed by Michael Lembeck.
When her niece is cast in The Philadelphia Ballet’s production of the Nutcracker, a jaded
ex-ballerina is forced to come to terms with the life and love she left behind.
Lily, played by Amy Acker.
Mark, played by Sascha Radetsky.
Sadie, played by Sophia Lucia.
Beth, played by Katherine Barrell.
Sharon, played by Shauna MacDonald.
Carol, played by Catherine Mary Stewart.
The Nutcracker, also known as George Balanchine's The Nutcracker, is a 1993 American Christmas
ballet film based on Peter Martins's stage production and directed by Emile Ardolino.
It stars Darci Kistler, Damian Woetzel, Kyra Nichols, Bart Robinson Cook, Macaulay Culkin, Jessica Lynn
Cohen, Wendy Whelan, Margaret Tracey, Gen Horiuchi, Tom Gold, and the New York City Ballet.
The film was released by Warner Bros.
under their Warner Bros.
Family Entertainment label on November 24, 1993, four
days after director Ardolino died.
It received mixed reviews and was a box office
failure, grossing only $2 million.
The film explores themes of ex-lover, aunt niece
relationship, ballet dancer, betrayal, ballet.
The tone is emotional.